A Guide to the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad Records, 1834-1997
Library of Virginia
- Series I: General Administration, Management, 1834-1981, 8 cu.ft. and 17 volumes (Box 1-27)
  - I.B. Minutes, 1834-1981
    - I.B.3. Minute Files, Board of Directors 1881, 1900-1906, 1944-1974
      - Board Meeting 28 Jan 1966 (Box-folder 21:1)
      - Board Meeting 25 Mar 1966 (Box-folder 21:2)
      - Board Meeting 29 Jul 1966 (Box-folder 21:3)
      - Board Meeting 30 Sep 1966 (Box-folder 21:4)
      - Board Meeting 18 Nov 1966 (Box-folder 21:5)
      - Board Meeting 13 Jan 1967 (Box-folder 21:6)
      - Board Meeting 30 Mar 1967 (Box-folder 21:7)
      - Board Meeting 39 Sep 1967 (Box-folder 21:8)
      - Board Meeting 8 Dec 1967 (Box-folder 21:9)
      - Board Meeting 26 Jan 1968 (Box-folder 21:10)
      - Board Meeting 29 Mar 1968 (Box-folder 21:11)
      - Board Meeting 26 Jul 1968 (Box-folder 22:1)
      - Board Meeting 27 Sep 1968 (Box-folder 22:2)
      - Board Meeting 6 Dec 1968 (Box-folder 22:3)
      - Board Meeting 31 Jan 1969 (Box-folder 22:4)
      - Board Meeting 28 Mar 1969 (Box-folder 22:5)
      - Board Meeting 21 Apr 1969 (Box-folder 22:6)
      - Board Meeting 28 Jul 1969 (Box-folder 22:7)
      - Board Meeting 26 Sep 1969 (Box-folder 22:8)
      - Board Meeting 20 Nov 1969 (Box-folder 22:9)
      - Board Meeting 23 Jan 1970 (Box-folder 22:10)
      - Board Meeting 27 Mar 1970 (Box-folder 22:11)
      - Board Meeting 26 Aug 1970 (Box-folder 22:12)
      - Board Meeting 13 Nov 1970 (Box-folder 22:13)
      - Board Meeting 28 Jan 1971 (Box-folder 22:14)
      - Board Meeting 26 Mar 1971 (Box-folder 22:15)
      - Executive Committee Meeting 4 Jun 1971 (Box-folder 23:1)
      - Board Meeting 30 Jul 1971 (Box-folder 23:2)
      - Board Meeting 1 Oct 1971 (Box-folder 23:3)
      - Board Meeting 18 Nov 1971 (Box-folder 23:4)
      - Board Meeting 28 Jan 1972 (Box-folder 23:5)
      - Board Meeting 31 Mar 1972 (Box-folder 23:6)
      - Board Meeting 28 Jul 1972 (Box-folder 23:7)
      - Executive Committee Meeting 5 Sep 1972 (Box-folder 23:8)
      - Board Meeting 29 Sep 1972 (Box-folder 23:9)
      - Board Meeting 17 Nov 1972 (Box-folder 23:10)
      - Board Meeting 25 Jan 1973 (Box-folder 23:11)
      - Board Meeting 30 Mar 1973 (Box-folder 23:12)
      - Board Meeting 27 Jul 1973 (Box-folder 23:13)
      - Board Meeting 29 Nov 1973 (Box-folder 23:14)
      - Board Meeting 18 Jan 1974 (Box-folder 23:15)
      - Board Meeting 29 Mar 1974 (Box-folder 23:16)
      - Board Meeting 26 Jul 1974 (Box-folder 23:17)
      - Board Meeting 27 Sep 1974 (Box-folder 23:18)
      - Board Meeting 21 Nov 1974 (Box-folder 23:19)
    - I.B.4. Minute Files, Stockholders Annual Meetings 1864, 1897-1905, 1944-1973
      Minute files include some Wash. South. R.Y. Co. files. In addition to minutes, they contain annual report information, and financial statements. In some cases there are only lists of stockholders and powers of attorney. Printed meeting reports are included in the Annual Reports in the Finance Series III.B.2.
      - Advertising for Stockholders' Meeting - Clipping and order to advertise in Richmond Whig 17 Nov 1864 (Box-folder 24:1)
      - Stockholders Power of Attorney forms 1897-1900 (Box-folder 24:2)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 21 Nov 1898 (Box-folder 24:3)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 20 Nov 1899 (Box-folder 24:4-6)
        Includes powers of attorney for adjourned meetings of 14 March 1900 and 18 April 1900
      - Stockholders Adjourned Meeting 20 Dec 1899, 10 Jan 1900, 1 Feb 1900, 14 March 1900, and 18 Apr 1900 (Box-folder 24:7-8)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 19 Nov 1900 (Box-folder 24:9-10)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 18 Nov 1901 (Box-folder 24:11-12)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 17 Nov 1902 (Box-folder 24:13)
      - Stockholders Adjourned Meeting 16 Dec 1902 (Box-folder 24:14)
      - Stockholders Adjourned Meeting 16 Jan 1903 (Box-folder 24:15)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 16 Nov 1903 (Box-folder 25:1)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 21 Nov 1904 (Box-folder 25:2)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting Wash. South. R.Y.Co. 20 Nov 1905 (Box-folder 25:3)
      - Annual Meeting, adjourned 21 Nov-13 Dec 1905 (Box-folder 25:4-5)
        Includes obituary of E.T.D. Myers, and statistics.
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 17 Apr 1944 (Box-folder 25:6)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 16 Apr 1945 (Box-folder 25:7)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 15 Apr 1946 (Box-folder 25:8)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 17 Apr 1947 (Box-folder 25:9)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 19 Apr 1948 (Box-folder 25:10)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 17 Apr 1950 (Box-folder 25:11)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 16 Apr 1951 (Box-folder 25:12)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 21 Apr 1952 (Box-folder 25:13)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 20 Apr 1953 (Box-folder 25:14)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 19 Apr 1954 (Box-folder 25:15)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 18 Apr 1955 (Box-folder 25:16)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 15 Apr 1957 (Box-folder 25:17)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 21 Apr 1958 (Box-folder 25:18)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 8 Apr 1960 (Box-folder 25:19)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 17 Apr 1961 (Box-folder 25:20)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 16 Apr 1962 (Box-folder 25:21)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 15 Apr 1963 (Box-folder 25:22)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 20 Apr 1964 (Box-folder 25:23)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 17 Apr 1967 (Box-folder 25:24)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 19 Apr 1971 (Box-folder 25:25)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 17 Apr 1972 (Box-folder 25:26)
      - Stockholders Annual Meeting 15 Apr 1973 (Box-folder 25:27)
  - I.C. Miscellaneous Records 1901-1911, 1 volume and .45 cu.ft. (Box 26-27)
    - History of the R.F. & P. Railroad, W.H. White, President 1911, 1 vol; 2 copies (Box 26)
      Includes General History of the R.F. & P. and its relation to the Commonwealth of Virginia, compiled upon request of the company's State Proxies; Charter and other acts relating to the R.F. & P., comp. 1881; Financial Statement, 1911; Remarks of W.H. White, President, before the Joint Committee on roads of the Senate and House of Delegates, 1908; Statement of the Interest of the Commonwealth in the R.F. & P.R.R. Co., 1908
    - Journal of Events 26 Nov 1901-3 Nov 1905, 1 vol. 4 pages entered (Box 25)
    - Secretary's Office - Authority for Destruction of Records
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 7 Aug 1940-30 Apr 1945 (Box-folder 27:1)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 8 Jun 1945-23 Jul 1951 (Box-folder 27:2)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 4 Sep 1951-1 Dec 1954 (Box-folder 27:3)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 29 Dec 1954-24 Mar 1959 (Box-folder 27:4)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 25 Mar 1959-14 Nov 1966 (Box-folder 27:5)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 14 Nov 1966-7 Aug 1969 (Box-folder 27:6)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 12 Feb 1970-17 Apr 1975 (Box-folder 27:7)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 8 May 1975-8 Sep 1976 (Box-folder 27:8)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 28 Sep 1976-9 Jul 1979 (Box-folder 27:9)
      - Authority for Destruction of Records 25 Jan 1980-24 Mar 1987 (Box-folder 27:10)
- Series II: Legal Department 1834-1986, 12.8 cubic feet and 26 volumes. (Box 28-63)
  This series is made up of five subseries: Charters and Bylaws; Cases, Claims, and Dockets; Contracts; Real Estate Files; and Miscellaneous Files. In addition to a copy of the 1834 Charter, this collection contains several amended versions (1924, 1949), as well as various Bylaws (1947-1983). The case files, 1981-1992, concern cases in state and federal courts, and contain briefs, appendices, petitions, pleadings, trial transcripts, motions, and statements of facts. They are organized by court and within chronologically. The entries in the two Claim Books, 1888-1889 concern compensation requests by customers, predominantly for loss or damage of freight, entered on a daily basis. The dockets, 1920-1938, issued by and addressed to the Interstate Commerce Commission deal predominantly with property valuation issues. Included is one correspondence file, 1968. Contracts, 1867-1969, include contract files, 1871-1969 (agreements, merger agreements, contracts, deeds, mortgages, statements, certified extracts of minutes, trusts; in many cases amendments, additions, and revisions - organized according to internal numbering system) and mixed volumes, 1867-1950 that are composed of a mixed set of legal documents, as well as Credit Bond Files, n.d., 1916-1942. This subseries gives a good impression of the business relationships, clients, and partners of the R.F.& P. The following subseries, the Real Estate Files, n.d., 1929-1986, includes copies and drafts of agreements, deeds, correspondence, plats and plans,
  - II.A. Charters and Bylaws 1834-1983
    - Charter 1834 (Box-folder 28:1)
    - Charter and Amendments Thereto 1924 (Box-folder 28:2)
    - Charter and Amendments Thereto to 1924, and Certificate of Amendment [...] 1949, 2 copies (Box-folder 28:3)
    - Bylaws, As of 21 Apr 1947 (Box-folder 28:4)
    - Bylaws, As of 17 Apr 1967 (Box-folder 28:5)
    - Bylaws, As of 29 May 1970, 27 Feb 1981 (Box-folder 28:6)
    - Bylaws, As of 18 Apr 1983 (Box-folder 28:7)
  - II.B. Cases, Claims, and Dockets 1888-1889, 1981-1991
    - II.B.1. Cases 1981-1992
      Organized by court, then chronologically; they include some or all of the following: briefs, appendices, petitions, pleadings, trial transcripts, motions, and statement of facts
      - Circuit Court of the City of Richmond (Box-folder 29-31:1-4)
      - Supreme Court of the United States 1992, one booklet, two copies (Box-folder 31:1)
      - Supreme Court of Virginia at Richmond 1981, No. 781820 (Box-folder 31:2-4)
      - Supreme Court of Virginia at Richmond 1990, No. 891135 (Box-folder 32:1-2)
      - United States Claims Court 1991, No. 90-750L; 2 folders (box 32) and 2 volumes (box 32 and 33) (Box-folder 32-33:1-2)
      - United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit 1991, No. 91-3003 (Box-folder 33:1-5)
    - II.B.2 Claims 1888-1889
      - Claim book K 12 Jun 1888-12 Feb 1889, 1 vol. (Box 34)
      - Claim book L 18 Jan 1889-8 Aug 1889, 1 vol. (Box 35)
    - II.B.3 Dockets 1920-1938, 1968
      - Valuation Docket/Finance Docket
        Labeled "Do Not Destroy." Refers to the R.F. & P. R.R. and the R.F. & P. and the R. & P. R.R. Connection Co.; also included are correspondence and accounting reports. Arranged according to their original filing order.
        - Interstate Commerce Commission: Accounting Report, Date of Valuation 30 June 1916, Prepared 1922 (Box-folder 36:1)
        - Interstate Commerce Commission: Revisions to Accounting Report, 1930 (Box-folder 36:2)
        - Interstate Commerce Commission: Revisions to Engineering Report 1923 (Box-folder 36:3)
        - Interstate Commerce Commission: Summary of Land Report 1922 (Box-folder 36:4)
          Includes excerpts and revised pages
        - Interstate Commerce Commission: Grant Summary of Reproduction Costs, excerpts 1920 (Box-folder 36:5)
        - Interstate Commerce Commission 8 July 1924 (Box-folder 36:6)
          Valuation Docket No. 372, Tentative Valuation Report on the Properties of the R.F. & P. R.R. Co., as of June 30, 1916
        - Interstate Commerce Commission, Relative Thereto, 1924 (Box-folder 36:7)
          Valuation Docket No. 372, Tentative Final Valuation Report as of June 30, 1916 and Order of the Commission Entered July 8, 1924
        - Before the Interstate Commerce Commission (Box-folder 36:8)
          Valuation Docket No. 372, Protest Against Said Tentative Valuation, Made and Filed by the R.F. & P. R.R., filed 2 Sept. 1924
        - Before the Interstate Commerce Commission 1 Oct. 1925 (Box-folder 36:9)
          Valuation Docket No. 372, Valuation Docket No. 393: In the Matter of the Tentative Valuation..., Brief for Carrier in Support of Protest, E. Randolph Williams, General Counsel
        - Before the Interstate Commerce Commission 1 Oct. 1925 (Box-folder 36:10)
          Valuation Docket No. 372, Valuation Docket 393: In the Matter of the Tentative Valuation...., Abstract of Evidence, E. Randolph Williams, General Counsel
        - Before the Interstate Commerce Commission 20 Dec 1925 (Box-folder 36:11)
          Valuation Docket No. 372, Valuation Docket 393: In the Matter of the Tentative Valuation..., Reply Brief for Carrier, E. Randolph Williams, General Counsel
        - Before the Interstate Commerce Commission 15 June 1926 (Box-folder 36:12)
          Finance Docket 3898 In the Matter of the Excess Income of the R.F. & P. R.R. Co., Brief for Carrier, E. Randolph Williams General Counsel
        - Before the Interstate Commerce Commission 15 April 1930 (Box-folder 36:13)
          Finance Docket 3898, In the Matter of the Excess Income of the R.F. & P. R.R. Co. Supplemental Brief for Carrier, E. Randolph Williams, Edwin F. Wendt, Consulting Engineer
        - Association of American Railroads, to Chief Accounting and Engineering Officers and R.F. & P. R.R. Comptroller, Letters 8 Aug 1968 (Box-folder 36:14)
    - Misc. Dockets 1930-1938
      These two dockets were not included in the docket file; they are listed in chronological order
      - Interstate Commerce Commission, Valuation Docket No. 327, R.F. & P. R.R. Co. et A1 1930 (Box-folder 36:15)
        Submitted 21 Dec 1925, decided 31 Jan 1930; copy of P.A. Rice, labeled "Final Value R.F. & P. R.R. Co. and Washington Southern R.Y."
      - Before the Interstate Commerce Commission, Finance Docket No. 12162, filed Sept 1938 (Box-folder 36:16)
  - II.C. Contracts 1867-1969
    Includes contract files (agreements, contracts, deeds, mortgages, statements, certified extracts of minutes, trusts; in many cases amendments, additions, and revisions) and volumes that are composed of a mixed set of legal documents, as well as credit bond files
    - II.C.1. Contract Files 1871-1969
      The following groups of contract files is arranged according to their original internal filing structure. Some files contain several different contract versions, updates, and/or multiple copies. RT refers to contract of the Rchmond Terminal R.Y. Co. Items without filing number have been placed at the end of this section in chronological order.
      - Contract 33 (Agreement) 1903 (Box-folder 37:1)
      - Contract 137 1904 (Box-folder 37:2)
      - Contract 231 (Action) 1901 (Box-folder 37:3)
      - Contract 429 (Agreement) 1907, 1924 (Box-folder 37:4)
      - Contract 474, 474 A 1931, 1946, 1949 (Box-folder 37:5)
      - Contract 485 (Agreement) 1909, 1917 (Box-folder 37:6)
      - Contract 487 (Agreement), revised 1910 (Box-folder 37:7)
      - Contract 761 1919 (Box-folder 37:8)
      - Contract 765 (Agreement) 1920 (Box-folder 37:9)
      - Contract 785 (Agreement) 1920 (Box-folder 37:10)
      - Contract 821 (Agreements) 1920 (Box-folder 37:11)
      - Contract 852 (Amending 759) 1912, 1920, 1921, 1923 (Box-folder 37:12-13)
      - Contract 852 A 1942 (Box-folder 37:14)
      - Contract 1010 (Plan of Accounting and Agreement) 1927, 1952 (Box-folder 38:1)
      - Contract 1047 1920, 1927 (Box-folder 38:2)
      - Contract 1053 (Mortgage) 1903 (Box-folder 38:3)
      - Contract 1054 (Mortgage) 1890 (Box-folder 38:4)
      - Contract 1175 (Classified statement) 1889 (Box-folder 38:5)
      - Contract 1279 (Agreement) 1938 (Box-folder 38:6)
      - Contract 1312 (Agreement) 1940 (Box-folder 38:7)
      - Contract 1371 1943 (Box-folder 38:8)
      - Contract 1428 (Mortgage) (Box-folder 38:9)
      - Contract 1515 (Agreement) 1948 (Box-folder 38:10)
      - Contract 1531 (Agreement) 1923 (Box-folder 38:11)
      - Contract 1537 1913 (Box-folder 38:12)
      - Contract 1538 (Agreement) 1954 (Box-folder 38:13)
      - Contract 154-? (Agreement; see also C 821) 1922 (Box-folder 39:1)
      - Contract 1544 (Certified extracts from minutes) 1921 (Box-folder 39:2)
      - Contract 1546 (Agreement) 1918, 1919 (Box-folder 39:3)
      - Contract 1563 (Amendment to Charter) 1949 (Box-folder 39:4)
      - Contract 1576 1949 (Box-folder 39:5)
      - Contract 1591 (Agreement) 1949 (Box-folder 39:6)
      - Contract 1902 (Agreement) 1959 (Box-folder 39:7)
      - Contract 2300 (Agreement) 1967, 1969 (Box-folder 39:8)
      - RT - C - 64 (Mortgage) 1922 (Box-folder 39:9)
      - RT - 64 (Agreement) 1922 (Box-folder 39:10)
      - RT - 67 (Mortgage) 1940, 1965 (Box-folder 39:11)
      - RT - 129 (Agreement) 1969 (Box-folder 39:12)
      - Deed 812 27 May and 5 Dec 1871 (Box-folder 40:1)
      - Agreement 3 Mar 1890 (Box-folder 40:2)
      - Deed 830 1 June 1903 (Box-folder 40:3)
      - Agreement 1918 (Box-folder 40:4)
      - Agreement 1920 (Box-folder 40:5)
      - Agreement 1922 (Box-folder 40:6)
      - Agreement 1924 (Box-folder 40:7)
      - Agreement 1926 (Box-folder 40:8)
      - Agreement 1928 (Box-folder 40:9)
      - Agreement 1934 (Box-folder 40:10)
      - Agreement 1939 (Box-folder 40:11)
    - II.C.2. Contracts - Mixed Volumes 1867-1950
      Arranged chronologically
      - Contracts and Agreements, manuscript, indexed 1867-1905, 1 vol. (Box 41)
      - Mortgages, 1871, 1890, and 1903; and Agreement of Merger, Wash. South R.T. Co. into the R.F. & P. R.R., 2 Feb 1920 1871-1920, 1 vol. (Box 42)
        Includes two loose-leaf typescript copies of the 1871 Mortgage
      - Bylaws; Charter; Stocks and Obligations, 30 Jun 1889; Deeds - Guaranteed Stock, 27 May 1871, 5 De. 1871; Consolidated Mortgage, 1 Apr 1890 (L.T. Oliver's copy) 1871-1890, 1 vol. (Box 42)
      - Charter, Bylaws, Mortgages, etc. 1881-1912, 1 vol. (Box 42)
        Includes copy of 1881 Charter; Classified Statement of Stocks, Dividend Obligations, Dividend Scrip, and Bonds and Certificates of Debt, outstanding 1889; Consolidated Gold Mortgage, 1890; General Gold Mortgage, 1903; Richmond-Washington Co. Collateral Trust Mortgage; Agreement, 1903; 3 copies; one copy includes table of content and single pages of Acts of Assembly, Mar 1912
      - Agreements 1891-1940, 1 vol. (Box 43)
        Includes agreements with the following: Wash. South R.Y. Co., Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Co., Southern R.Y. Co., Atlantic Coast Line R.R., Pennsylvania R.R. Co., and Seaboard Air Line Railway
      - Arbitration Proceedings between A.C.L. R.R. Co. and R.F. & P. R.R. Co. 1919-1937, 1 vol. (Box 43)
        Under Agreement dated 6 Jan 1919, Robert B. Tunstall, Sole Arbitrator, 1937. Includes determination, opinion, stipulation and exhibits, reporter's transcript, and memoranda
      - Issue of $5,417,400 Face Amount of Divident Obligations as of 1 Feb 1923 1923, 1 vol. (Box 43)
        Includes Application to Interstate Commerce Commission, approvals, certificates, receipt, resolutions, opinion, and copies of financial records
      - Agreements (various Railroads) 1901-1927, 1 vol. (Box 43)
        Potomac Yard Agreement, 31 Dec 1927; Six Party Agreement Incorporating Richmond-Washington Co., 31 Jun 1901; James River Branch, Agreement, 6 Jan 1919; Wash. South. R.Y. Co. Trackage Agreement, 17 Sept 1901; Washington Terminal Agreement, 27 Jul 1904; Phil Balt. & Wash. R.R. Co. and Wash. South. R.Y. Co., Agreement re: Handling Freight Traffic in D.C., 3 Oct 1917; one loose-leaf typescript copy of the Wash. South. R.Y. Co. Trackage Agreement, 17 Sep 1901
      - Railroad Equipment Trust, Series 1938 1937-1938, 2 copies; 1 vol. (Box 44)
        Compilation of 32 documents; includes Application to the Interstate Commerce Commission, letters, a report and order, Equipment Trust Agreement and Lease, certificates, agreements, opinions, receipts, notices, opinions, a guarantee, bill of sale, indemnification, and designation
      - General Mortgage Dated as of 1 Mar 1941 to First & National Bank, Trustee 1941, 2 copies; 1 vol. (Box 45)
        Compilation of 54 documents; includes Application to Interstate Commerce Commission, letters, report and order, balance sheets, maps, financial statements, minutes, purchase agreements, certificates, waivers, acknowledgements, reciepts, notices, opinion, extracts from bylaws, deeds of discharge and release, and memorandum
      - R.F. & P. R.R. - American Car Foundry Co., Condidtional Sales Agreement, Agreement and Assignment 1947, Finance docket No. 15868 1947, 2 copies; 1 vol. (Box 46)
        Includes application to Interstate Commerce Commission, correspondence, report and order, final settlement, certificate of delivery and acceptance, conditional sales agreement, agreement and assignment, opinion, certificate of notification, report
      - [Issuance of three negotiable] Notes dated April 15 1947; $1,995,000 1947, 2 copies; 1 vol. (Box 46)
        Includes Application to Interstate Commerce Commission, opinion, bylaws, resolutions, notes, estimated expenses, notices of sale, correspondence, amended application, report and order, and statements
      - Railroad Equipment Trust, Series 1948 1948, 2 copies; 1 vol. (Box 46)
        Consists of notice and invitation for bids, awarding of contract, Application to Interstate Commerce Commission, opinion, financial statements, letters, orders, certificates, closing papers, memoranda, receipts, agreements, bill of sale
      - United States of America V. Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, et al., Railroad Strike of May 1948 1948, 1 vol. (Box 47)
      - Conditional Sale Agreement with General Motors Corporation (E/M Division), 15 Oct 1949, Agreements and Assignment between General Motors Corporation (E/M Division) and the First National Bank of the City of New York, 17 Oct 1949 1949, 2 copies; 1 vol. (Box 47)
        Includes resolution, purchase agreement, invitation to bid, bid and acceptance, resolutions, certificates, conditional sale agreement, agreement and assigment, opinions, form letter of notification, form of acknowledgement, form of bill of sale, statement of final unit price
      - Certificate of Amendment to the Charter and Certificate of Decrease of Actually Issued and Outstanding Capital Stock & Captial for Issuance of New Stock on Four-for-One Basis 1949-1950, 2 copies; 1 vol. (Box 48)
        Includes resolution of directors, notice to stockholders, letters, Application to the Interstate Commerce Commission, opinion, certificates, finacial date, report and order, specimen of new stock certificates, mortgages
    - II.C.3. Credit Bonds & Bonds Covering "Order Notify" Shipments n.d., 1916-1942
      Also included are Surety Bonds; Arranged in original, alphabetical filing order
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds A-Am (Box-folder 49:1)
        Includes: A.A. Harvey, Bond, 14 Oct 1926; American Express, Traveler's Checks, 3 Sep 1926; American Locomotive Co.; Bond, 29 Jul 1918; and letter, 23 Sep 1921
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds An-Bo (Box-folder 49:2)
        Includes: Anderson Automobile Co., Bond, 9 Nov 1927; Bad Axe Grain Co., Indemnity Bond, 8 May 1936; Banker Trust Company, Traveler's Checks, 8 Dec 1926; Bone Dry Fertilizer Co., Bond, 8 May 1936
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds Bu-Cha (Box-folder 49:3)
        Includes: Burton & Briel, Bond (not included, correspondence only), ca. 1929 and 1930; C.F. Sauer Co., Bond, 13 May 1925; Canadian Pacific Express Company, Traveler's Checks, 1 Sep 1926; Chase City Mfg. Co., Bond, 24 Apr 1925, 2 Oct 1925
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds Che-Cr (Box-folder 49:4)
        Includes: Chero-Cola Co., Indemnity Bond, 25 Aug 1925; Bond, 6 Oct 1926; Clyde Eby & Sons, Bond, 17 Sep 1936; Craig-Huff & Co., Bonds, 24 Mar 1926; Crawford Manufacturing Co., Bond, 7 Sep 1934
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds D-E (Box-folder 49:5)